<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antequated - maps for the rest of us</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Antequated - maps for the rest of us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get antequated with SOmap</title>
      <link>/2019/03/21/get-antequated-with-somap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/21/get-antequated-with-somap/</guid>
      <description>Polar maps! Last time we got this far by creating a very simplistic polar map and discussing some of the difficulties in customizing and finishing it. Since then Dale Maschette discussed these problems at useR Brisbane 2018 and stirred up multiple discussions on twitter about the joys of polar maps.
Behold SOmap.
SOmap::SOmap() ## Loading required namespace: rgeos  SOmap To install the SOmap package use
remotes::install_github(&amp;quot;AustralianAntarcticDivision/SOmap&amp;quot;) and see the package readme and documentation for further details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>polar maps now!</title>
      <link>/2017/06/14/polar-maps-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/14/polar-maps-now/</guid>
      <description>Map projections are a hot topic! What do we need?
a data manipulation and visualization environment coordinate transformation tools a coordinate reference system (‘crs’) data  Here they are:
## 1. R is a data manipulation and visualization environment ## R can do work with map projections using extension packages ## install.packages(&amp;quot;sf&amp;quot;) ## install.packages(&amp;quot;rnaturalearth&amp;quot;) ## 2. sp and rgdal provide map data manipulation and transformation library(sp) library(rgdal) ## rgdal: version: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello-antequated</title>
      <link>/2017/06/13/hello-antequated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/13/hello-antequated/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Antequated.org We love maps. We love polar maps. We love the world as it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 23:36:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a blogdown website dedicated to producing maps nearer the poles. The antequated philosophy rails against the injustices of tropical-bias and rejects any notion of &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;down&amp;rdquo;, or indeed any kind of stability at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a general Southern Ocean map</title>
      <link>/2017/03/08/general-southern-ocean-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/08/general-southern-ocean-map/</guid>
      <description>Editorial note: This work is carried out using generally available R packages from CRAN. The content in this document was prepared before it was published, and in this form it may again be updated. There’s also a step where some CCAMLR polygons are read in from shapefiles that must be manually downloaded. In future we can remove this requirement and make things much easier. 
Get ready Required R packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>